MAHBUBUR RAHMAN

mahbuburahman.github.io | mahabub708@gmail.com

Overview & research interest

I am a senior software product manager at Crowdbotics (low code/no code platform). My research interest is designing large scale intelligent software system, find patterns and reuse. In terms of software products, my interest is to design AI-driven components that can help both individuals and communities solve their problems. Through the application of various analytical tools and meticulously designed algorithms, I would like to expand my expertise by incorporating my skills into academic and industrial projects with practical applications.

EDUCATION

Eastern University Bangladesh B.Sc. in Computer Science and Engineering CGPA: 3.01/4.00

2015-2019

2018-2019

Institute of Modern Language, Dhaka University *A1 Spanish Language*

EXPERIENCE

Crowdbotics Senior Technical Product Manager Remote - 2020-Present

- Led successful integration of gRPC based complex backend APIs and lead the entire development team, after publish the app Company was acquired for \$115 million.
- Design and implement scope template and estimation process where development cost reduced 20%
- Successfully delivered 5 complex mobile and web app within 2 years of span along with 70% profit margin

Backbone Offices Technology Officer Remote-2017-2020

- Maintain and develop website for co-working space, integrate 3rd party APIs for booking space and negotiate vendors with different purchase.
- Reduce main and development cost 50% by using right technology and requirement analysis.

Upwork Freelance Product Manager & Developer

Remote - 2018-2020

- Completed 50+ successful freelancer jobs with a rating of 4.9 overall within 5
- Top Rated Plus freelancer (top 3% among more than 16 millions freelancers in upwork)

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

- Win a grant of one million taka for my own startup idea from iDEA Bangladesh (Govt. VC in Bangladesh). Write python code and play around with cloud computing with best practices. Passionate about technologies and always love to learn something new